Statistics

Descriptive Analysis Exploratory Analysis Simulation Studies Time Series Forecasting **Trend Analysis**

Data Wrangling

CSVKit

Google Apps Script

Google Forms

Google Sheets

HTML

JavaScript

ISON

Microsoft Excel

Microsoft Power Query M

NumPy

Pandas

PySpark

Python

REST APIs

SQLAlchemy

VBA

Data Visualisation

Business Intelligence Dashboards Databricks SQL Data Storytelling

Inkscape

Jasper Reports Jupyter Notebooks

Matplotlib

Microsoft Power BI

Microsoft PowerPoint

Operational Reporting

OlikView

Streamlit

Data Management

Data Lakes

Data Lakehouse

Database Administration

Database Design

Microsoft Access

Microsoft SQL Server

MySQL Database

Oracle Database

PL/pgSQL

PL/Python

PL/SQL

PostgreSQL Database

Query Optimisation

SQL

SQLite

Stored Procedures

Cloud

AWS CloudFormation

AWS CloudWatch

AWS EC2

AWS RDS AWS S3

CircleCI

Databricks

Infrastructure-as-Code

Jamie Littlejohn **Data Analyst/Developer**

jamie.littlejohn@outlook.com github.com/jamie-littlejohn linkedin.com/in/jamie-littlejohn 07951169814

I'm an ever-learning data analyst and developer offering user-friendly solutions to everyone's favourite data questions - "What does this mean?" and "How do we use it?". I have over seven years experience in data storytelling, forecasting and data migration projects having worked for a number of large companies across the UK innovating critical business data processes.

I specialise in SQL/Python development with a solid background in delivering actionable intelligence and business value with Excel and Power BI too.

Work Experience

Systems Analyst @ Gousto

Jun 2021 - Nov 2022

Warehouse Management and Automation Control Systems - supporting core factory operations and driving strategic improvements across our supply chain processes.

Developing PL/SQL features and SQL reports for Dispatcher WMS, leveraging continuous integration and continuous deployments with Github/CircleCI/AWS.

Squad Health Metrics - Google Forms/Sheets, Power BI data model and dashboard for open insight into employee satisfaction.

AWS RDS Oracle Database 12c and Amazon Linux end-of-life upgrades and their regression testing with external integrations.

Databricks SQL & Power BI dashboards developed to distribute the operational reporting workload away from production servers.

Factory Analyst @ Gousto

Sep 2020 - Jun 2021

Dispatcher WMS analysis using Jasper Reports. Monitoring system/supply chain issues to reduce operational losses via real-time reporting.

Data Analyst @ Greencore

Sep 2018 - Aug 2020

Agency labour forecasting based on variable-length temporary working contracts (Greencore Award Nomination for Business Effectiveness).

Bill of Material standard costings and yield validation project with the Logistics and Master Data teams (Greencore Award Winner for Business Effectiveness).

System21 ERP analysis - VBA, SQL and data migration with Excel and Access. Advanced Excel support (Greencore Award Nomination for People at Greencore).

Analysing and interpreting large data sets and validating the accuracy of data kept. Labour, waste and operational performance data mining.

Data quality process reform, leading and supporting the development of the Production Admin team to facilitate data integrity.

Business improvement experience conducting Line Observations, recording downtimes and using the data for root-cause and Pareto analysis. Optimal manning observation studies.

Distributing the daily and weekly Material Usage Variance and Operational reports for the Senior Leadership and Operations teams. Investigating efficiency and financial losses within the factory and providing technical support on projects to automate work flows.

Software Engineering

Algorithms

Acceptance Testing

Database Development

Data Modelling

Declarative Programming

Functional Programming

Object-Oriented Programming

Procedural Programming

Regression Testing

Requirements Analysis

Systems Development

Developer Tools

AWS CLI

DBeaver

Docker

Git

Jupyter Console

Lua Scripting

Neovim

Linux

Amazon/CentOS/Fedora

Bash Scripting

Debian/Ubuntu

Hardware

Networking

Security

SSH

System Administration

Virtualisation

Domain Knowledge

Automation Control Systems

Business Improvement

Continuous Improvement

ERP Systems

Food Manufacturing

Management Information

Supply Chain Management

Warehouse Management

Collaboration Tools

ClickUp

Confluence

GitHub

Google Meets

Iira

Microsoft Teams

Miro

Slack

Interpersonal Skills

Incident Management

Project Management

Requirements Analysis

Stakeholder Management

Personal Interests

Artificial Intelligence

Automation

Blockchain

Gaming

Home-schooling

Modding

Open Source Software Remote Working

Career Break (Medical)

Sep 2017 - Sep 2018

Data Analyst @ Bakkavor

Mar 2017 - Sep 2017

System Administrator @ Osborn Consulting

Sep 2016 - Mar 2017

Data Analyst @ Princes

Mar 2016 - Sep 2016

Management Information Analyst @ WorldStores

Sep 2015 - Mar 2016

Qualifications

In Progress - Dataquest - Data Scientist

In Progress - Dataquest - Data Engineer

2022 - Dataquest - Business Analyst with Power BI

2022 - Databricks - Lakehouse Fundamentals

2022 - LinkedIn - Advance Your Skills in SQL

2022 - LinkedIn - Become a Business Intelligence Specialist

2022 - LinkedIn - Become a Data Analyst

2022 - LinkedIn - Become a Data Analytics Specialist

2021 - LinkedIn - Become a Data Scientist

2022 - LinkedIn - Become a Full-Stack Web Developer

2022 - LinkedIn - Become a Power BI Specialist

2022 - LinkedIn - Become a Programmer: Foundations

2022 - LinkedIn - Become a RESTful API Developer

2022 - LinkedIn - Become a Software Developer

2022 - LinkedIn - Become a Web Developer

2021 - LinkedIn - Build Essential Data Skills

2021 - LinkedIn - Build Your Analytical Skills with Statistical Analysis

2021 - LinkedIn - Build Your Data Analysis Skills

2022 - LinkedIn - Develop Your Data Analysis Skills

2022 - LinkedIn - Explore a Career in Database Development

2021 - LinkedIn - Explore a Career in SQL Development 2022 - LinkedIn - Getting Started with Agile Software Development

2022 - LinkedIn - Getting Started with Linux

2022 - LinkedIn - Getting Started with Python

2021 - LinkedIn - Hands-On Data Science

2021 - LinkedIn - Managing you Career as a Developer

2022 - LinkedIn - Master Dashboards and Data Viz in Power BI

2022 - LinkedIn - Master Microsoft Power BI

2022 - LinkedIn - Master SQL Development

2021 - LinkedIn - Master SQL for Data Science

2022 - LinkedIn - Master the Concepts of Data Visualization and Storytelling

2022 - LinkedIn - Mastering Executive-Level Data Analytics

2022 - LinkedIn - Software Development Fundamentals

2021 - LinkedIn - Starting Your Career in Tech: Data Science

2021 - LinkedIn - Starting Your Career in Tech: Software Development

2021 - LinkedIn - Succeed as a Remote Software Developer

Discontinued - Nottingham Trent University - BSc Data Science

2012 - AQA - GCSE Methods in Mathematics

2012 - AQA - GCSE Applications of Mathematics

2012 - AQA - GCSE English Language

2012 - AQA - GCSE English Literature

2012 - AQA - GCSE Engineering (Double Award)

2012 - AQA - GCSE Biology

2012 - AQA - GCSE Chemistry

2012 - AQA - GCSE Physics

2012 - AQA - GCSE German

2012 - Edexcel - GCSE Business Studies and Economics

2012 - Edexcel - Functional Skills Level 2 ICT

2011 - Edexcel - Functional Skills Level 2 English

2009 - AQA - Functional Skills Level 2 Mathematics